

## CONTACT

- Vilnius
- **a** +37067632152
- ☑ dariusnaw@gmail.com
- **in** LinkedIn
- **O** GitHub
- Portfolio

## **HOBBIES**

- Programing
- Traveling
- Outdoor activities
- Audio books
- Gym

# DARIUS NAVICKAS

JUNIOR FRONT-END DEVELOPER

#### **ABOUT ME**

I am highly interested in programming because of its challenges and learning possibilities. As I am willing to change my career I successfully completed Front-End Engineering course at BIT. This led me to be actively learning different technologies and tools in my course and on my own to become a better programmer. I am passionate about IT and eager to dive deeper. I have 10 years of experience in sales management, what helped me to master my problem solving, decision making and time planing skills, good communication skills, which I believe is very important in IT industry.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### 2022.05 - 2022 08

#### 2022.05 - 2022. "Community Blog" University project

Front-End Developer

- Write clean, efficient, and maintainable code while following industry best practices and coding standards.
- Use front-end development technologies and techniques to build scalable, high-performance web applications, including frameworks such as React.
- Work closely with the UI/UX design team to create responsive, accessible, and visually appealing interfaces that provide an exceptional user experience.
- Contribute to the continuous improvement of the team's Agile processes, including suggesting improvements to sprint planning, backlog refinement, working with Jira tasks and contributing to other Agile ceremonies.
- Work with version control systems like Git to manage codebase changes and collaborate with other developers, using branching and merging strategies to ensure code quality and maintain a stable development environment.
- Participate in code reviews to provide and receive constructive feedback to improve the quality of the codebase.

#### 2020.09 - Prese UAB Iceco trade

nt

Senior Sales manager

- Close collaboration with existing clients and completion of their needs
- Active search of new clients opportunities
- Negotiation for the best offer between two parties
- Active time and tasks planning based on various deadlines
- Daily decision making for various sales related concerns and edge cases
- Participating in problem solving for company wide and clients related issues by offering well analyzed soliutions
- Teamwork and personal challenges

## **EDUCATION**

Baltic institute of technology 2021 - 2022 Front-End Developer

Vilniaus kooper acijos kolegija **Business management** 

2012 - 2014

## **SKILLS**

HTML + CSS JavaScript ReactJS GitHub TypeScript





### **LANGUAGES**

Lithuanian English Russian

